

https://jeaster12.github.io

jeaster12@gmail.com

Profile

10+ years of Web and Front-End application development experience with strong working knowledge of core UX design process, principals, and techniques.

Advanced expertise in designing, prototyping, and developing from wireframes and interactions to production.

Demonstrated ability to work collaboratively in a team environment with engineers, analysts, marketing personnel, designers, and software developers. Ability to work independently with good organizational skills and the flexibility to adaptability to work on multiple projects and exceptional attention to detail.

Experience

Senior Associate Manager Software Engineering, IHS Markit; March 2019 - Present
As Product Owner/Lead developer for the Ipreo design system - I lead a team that is
involved in all stages of User Experience and User Interface development. We design,
build, and deliver the system that drives over 50 products. From whiteboards to sketch
to prototype to production!

Senior Associate Software Engineering, IHS Markit; August 2018 - March 2019

Lead UI Developer, Ipreo (Acquired by IHS Market August 2018); Jan. 2015 - Aug. 2018 Engaging product owners, designers, and developers to understand their use cases and help them build beautiful solutions as efficiently as possible. Utilize industry best practices, design, develop, document, and implement software solutions in accordance with project specifications, ensuring completion within the planned time constraint and meeting the established objectives for quality, reliability and performance.

Web Developer, SharedVue (Acquired by Zift Solutions); July 2014 - December 2014Designing and developing client showcases for leading tech companies including IBM, Intel, Citrix, Red Hat, Riverbed, VMware and SAP.

Front End Web Design and Development, M is Good; Sept. 2013-July 2014

Web Design - designing, building and launching websites for small businesses. Web development - programming, database administration, troubleshooting. Adding functionality to existing websites, maintaining and creating new site. Drupal, Wordpress, Squarespace, Kenitico, Html5, PHP, CSS,Sass, Less, javascript, jQuery, AJAX. Graphic Design - logos, signage, t-shirts, direct mail, social media.

Education

North Carolina State University – Webmaster Certification, 2012-2013 Living Arts College – Associate of Arts - Digital Media, 2008-2010